Guide to the Clarence Jack Konheim Photograph Collection 1930's-1960's PR 315
New-York Historical Society
Clarence Jack Konheim Photograph Collection
1930's-1950's
New-York Historical Society
PR 315
1.3 Linear feet (2 boxes, 64 photos)
Clarence Jack Konheim (1902-1968) was an amateur photographer and member of the Tudor City Camera Club. This collection contains 36 black and white photographs of New York City between the 1930's and 1960's. Subjects include Easter Sunday in Harlem, an elderly couple sunning themselves in winter in Coney Island, a window washer, an urban baseball game, and fishing from a pier.
Scope and Contents Note
This collection contains 64 black and white photographs of New York City scenes between the 1930's and 1960's. The photographs were taken by amateur photographer Clarence Jack Konheim (1902-1968). According to a 1953 Yale alumni publication, Konheim lived at 321 East 43rd Street and worked for the Grayson Whitney Corp. Several of the photographs bear stickers from the Metropolitan Camera Club and Tudor City Camera Club. Images are described in the container list below.
Access Restrictions
Available by advance appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Provenance
Gift of Linda Konheim Kramer, 2015
- Five men (African American and white) hanging out on railing, circa 1930's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
- United Nation Building with flagpoles, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
- Two men and a boy warming by a trash can fire on lower east side, circa 1940's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
- Laundry drying on lines between tenements, circa 1940's
- Fire escapes, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
- Reflection of buildings in United Nations Building, circa 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
- Building covered with posters, 1963 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
- 59th Street horse carriages at night, 1936 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
- Two Italian men sitting in front of donations at feast of San Gennaro, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
- Window washer, circa 1930's
- Couple sunning themselves in winter with reflector on Coney Island, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
- Salvation Army recruiting (2 photos), circa 1950 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
- Asian children (in Chinatown?), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
- Children (4 photos), circa 1930's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
- Easter in Harlem (8 photos), 1952 or 1953 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Urban baseball game, circa 1940's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
- Five boys fishing off pier, circa 1940's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
- "Blizzard" (men shoveling snow), circa 1940's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
- Abstract photo of railing and shadows, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
- Sculpture garden MOMA, circa 1950's (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
- "Tornado" (Coney Island), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
- "Rock-O-Plan" (Coney Island), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
- "Wonder wheel behind stock" (Coney Island), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
- "Wonder wheel behind bars" (Coney Island), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
- "Parachute jump" (Coney Island), undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
- Harbor view over parking lot, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
- Boats docked with view of skyline, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
- Harbor view with boats, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
- Harbor view with misty view of skyline, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
- Skyline view through grating, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
- Cars crossing bridge, circa 1940's (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
- Cars and people under elevated train tracks (2 photos), circa 1940 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
- Night view, elevated train tracks (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
- View from bridge, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
- City view with billboards and water tanks, circa 1940 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
- City view with bridges, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
- View over Brooklyn showing elevated train terminal on present site of Cadman Plaza, circa 1936 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
- Central Park, kids fishing (includes several African-American children), circa 1930's (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
- Central Park, feeding ducks and geese, circa 1930's (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
- Young boy on street, circa 1930's (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
- Slushy streets, New York (3 photos), circa 1940's (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
- Pennsylvania Station interior (2 photos), circa 1940's (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
- Industrial scenes, New York (2 photos), circa 1940's (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
- Trains in station, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
- Views of Empire State Building (3 photos), undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
- People on viewing platform?, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
- Workers painting Ritz crackers billboard on building, circa 1940's (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)